# BHARAT CHAUDHARI

#### **Senior System Administrator**

**Mobile:** + 91-73833 08615

E-mail: bchaudhari1110@gmail.com

Linkdin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bharat-chaudhari-817984313/

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:**

Experienced in Data Center Operation, Network and Server Support with over all 7 years of experience in the IT and Corporate industries. Excellent reputation for resolving problems and improving customer satisfaction. To enhance my knowledge and skills I am always ready to work in a challenging environment.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

**Cloud Platforms**: Azure, GCP, AWS

Windows Server: Active directory, DNS, DHCP, FTP, NFS, IIS, Group Policy, WSUS

Linux Server : Centos, Ubuntu, Apache, Nginx, NFS, SMB, SSL

**Hosting Panel**: WHM cPanel, Vestacp

Firewall : Fortinet, Sophos

VirtualizationAntivirus: VMware ESXi, vSphare, XCP-ng, Hyper-V: Symantec, TrendMicro, Bit Defender, Seqrite

Monitoring Tool: Zabbix, PRTG

**Backup Tool**: Acronis, Veem, Iperius, SQL Backup Master

Vapt Tool : Nessus Professional

**Scripting**: PowerShell, Bash, Python

#### **EXPERIENCE:**

1. ECS Biztech Ltd. (Data center) Duration: April 2022 to Till Date

Job Profile: IT - Senior System Administrator

- Managing Data Center Operations: Servers, Storage, Routers, Switches, and Health Monitoring, ISP Load Balance, Customer Bandwidth Monitoring by Using Tools PRTG, Hardware Monitoring Reports and Health Reports Check
- Public and Private Cloud Operations: ECS Private Cloud (New Virtual Machines Storage, RAM,
  CPU availability check, New VM Creations, and Delivery Management)
- Data Center Security Monitoring: Fortinet and Sophos Firewall Operations, Policy Creations as Per Customer Requirements for Port Access, Remote IP access, IPsec and SSL VPN implementation, public and private IP distribution management, LAN-to-WAN security monitoring, and implementation for company staff
- Configuration and Management of AD, Group Policy, DNS Server, FTP Server, DHCP Server, WSUS, WDS, IIS and Accounts Tally Server Security Operations
- Customers Data Backup operations on Windows and Linux Servers in Acronis Cyber Protect Backup Tool, NFS Sharing, SQL Database Backup
- Customers website hosting in using WHM cPanel
- Virtualization Manager: Hyper-V, ESXi Hypervisor, vCenter, XCP-ng Server

- Mail Server Operations: Support to Customer regarding mail server issue and migration operations for Zimbra, G-Suit and Office 365 mail platforms
- Hands on experience on Hardware Server Installation (HP, DELL Rack Servers)
- Provide support to customer on Windows and Linux server platform, WEB Hosting, Application, Network issues
- Providing on time support satisfactorily and escalating all the complaints and requirements by using tools for Customer Ticket Support and, monthly Servers Health Report for Customer
- 2. Aspire NXT Pvt. Ltd.

**Duration: August 2019 to April 2022** 

Job Profile: IT – Technical Support Engineer

- Proficient in installing & troubleshooting of Active Directory, DNS, DHCP & IIS Server on Microsoft Windows Environment
- Working knowledge with firewall device Fortigate
- Manage Antivirus Server: Symantec Endpoint Protection and MacAfee Endpoint
- Manage Zimbra mail server and G suite
- Performed Server Hardware failure monitoring by iDRAC, Raid Configuration and availability monitoring activity.
- Maintain Daily Server Checklist (Hard Disk Utilization, RAM Utilization, and CPU Utilization)
- Manage internal ticket system, provide solution as per user ticket issue
- Identify user issue, diagnosing problems and delivering workable solutions via phone and Email or Remote support
- 3. ANU Designers & Fabricators Pvt. Ltd.

**Duration: June 2017 to July 2019** 

Job Profile: IT – System Administrator

- Support of server Hardware, operating systems, Microsoft application software and Peripherals, Windows 2008, 2012 R2, Linux, Windows 7,8,10 (User Creation, Deletion, Password reset)
- Resolve network connectivity issue, Network device health check and maintenance
- Manage Network Security with Cyberoam Firewall for ISP Load Balancing, Web Filtering, Application Filtering
- Installation of Antivirus Endpoint Server, Patches & Update from Backend side & frontend both
- Perform Periodic User Data Backup
- Configuration as well as troubleshooting of MS-Outlook
- Configuration & Installation SAP B1 Client and also Performing Periodic Backup of SAP
- Configuration KVM switch Installation
- Installing and Configuration New Hardware & Software
- Consulting various Vendors in the activities of IT peripheral/infrastructure purchases like Modem, routers, switches, Racks, printer, Computer, Scanner and coordinate with Vendors.

## **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION:**

Msc.IT-IMS from Gujarat University in year 2017 with 6.62 CGPA